<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithms for the People</title>
    <link>http://algosforthepeople.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Algorithms for the People</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 11:31:46 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://algosforthepeople.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COINTELPRO</title>
      <link>http://algosforthepeople.org/posts/cointelpro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 11:31:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://algosforthepeople.org/posts/cointelpro/</guid>
      <description>This post is meant as a primer on COINTELPRO. A large part of the course was spent on the surveillance of social movements, but surveillance in general and surveillance of social movements in particular cannot be properly understood without some background on COINTELPRO.
Introduction In 1971, a group of activists called the Citizens&amp;rsquo; Commission to Investigate the FBI broke into an FBI office in Media, Pennsylvania. The group found over a thousand classified documents which they shared with the press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Moral Character of Scientific Work</title>
      <link>http://algosforthepeople.org/posts/moral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 11:31:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://algosforthepeople.org/posts/moral/</guid>
      <description>The first paper we covered was Phil Rogaway&amp;rsquo;s The Moral Character of Cryptographic Work. The paper centers around the moral and ethical responsibilities of cryptographers but its themes are relevant and applicable to computer science as a whole. This was a useful paper for us to discuss early in the course so that we could cover important notions for the rest of the course.
Summary The paper is divided into four parts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro &amp; Overview</title>
      <link>http://algosforthepeople.org/posts/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 11:31:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://algosforthepeople.org/posts/intro/</guid>
      <description>In Fall 2019, I taught a course called Crypto for Social Good. I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the name but I had to make a quick decision and that was the best I could come up with at the time. I had a sense of the topics I wanted to cover but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a way to capture the essence of the course.
In fact, on the first day of class I told my students:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>http://algosforthepeople.org/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://algosforthepeople.org/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>